A Finding Aid to the Anton Refregier Papers, circa 1900-circa 1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.refranto
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition Files, 1942-1981; Series 6; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 18-19
  - Exhibitions, 1958-1974; (9 folders) (Box 19, Folder 1-9)
  - Exhibitions and Lectures, 1970-1973 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Guest Book of Signatures (Unknown Exhibition), circa 1960s (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Invitation Lists for Openings, circa 1960s (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Personal Business Records, 1920s-1980s; Series 7; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 19-20
  Scattered but limited financial documentation relating to Refregier's work can be found throughout this series in addition to addresses in 6 sets of index cards including 3 alphabetical sets, and groupings for "Owners of my work," "Sources," "New materials and processes" and a mixed set.
  - Address Books, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 13-14)
  - Adresses/Business Cards, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (3 folders) (Box 19, Folder 15-17)
  - Adresses on Index Cards, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (2 shoeboxes of index cards) (Box 19, Folder 18-19)
  - Addresses on Index Cards, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Addresses for Greeting Cards, 1950s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Bills/Receipts, 1920s-1980s; (9 folders) (Box 20, Folder 4-12)
  - Financial Notes/Records, 1960s-1977; (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 13-14)
  - Health/Immunization Records, circa 1940s-circa 1970s (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Insurance Records, 1930s-1970s; (3 folders) (Box 20, Folder 16-18)
  - Insurance Claim, Theft of Artwork from Studio, 1972-1975 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous, circa 1930s-circa 1970s (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Property Records, 1931, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Record Book, Mexico, 1977-1978 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Tax Records, 1940s-1980s; (12 folders) (Box 20, Folder 23-34)
  - Tax Records, NY Sales Tax, 1960s-1970s (Box 20, Folder 35)
- Printed Material, circa 1920s-1980s; Series 8; 7.4 Linear feet Boxes 21-28, 36
  1.5 linear feet of printed material documenting Refregier's career can be found here, including invitations to events, exhibition announcements and catalogs and news clippings about the artist. Also found is printed material in which illustrations by Refregier were published.
  The remainder of the series consists of printed material reflecting Refregier's interest in subjects including art, literature, music, theater, and local, national and international politics, particularly in the countries of the Eastern bloc. The series contains issues of popular magazines such as Life and Look, newspapers such as The Worker, Daily Worker, and National Guardian, foreign publications such as Rumania Today, Korea, Neue Berliner Ilustrierte, and a folder of 2 tourist information brochures from circa 1933 Nazi Germany. News clippings from the series provide coverage of some of the most defining events of the twentieth century including World War II, events in the Soviet Union, John F. Kennedy's assasination, the Vietnam War, and the civil rights movement in the United States.
  Printed material relating to the World Council of Peace, includes records of related organizations, councils and committees, and includes Council bulletins, official statements, resolutions, articles and reports, minutes of meetings, and press releases.
  Printed material on miscellaneous other subjects includes some issues of the local Woodstock newspaper Woodstock Week and a small group of clippings files with Refregier's original labels.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  8.1: Printed Material, Refregier, circa 1920s-circa 1980s
  8.2: Printed Material, Other Artists/Art-Related, circa 1920s-1980s
  8.3: Printed Material, Other Subjects, circa 1920s-1980s
  - Printed Material, Refregier, circa 1920s-circa 1980s; 8.1
    - Announcements, Catalogs, Invitations, circa 1930s-1980s; (12 folders) (Box 21, Folder 1-12)
    - "Man of Art," Compilation of News Clippings on Refregier, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Postcards of Refregier's Artwork, 1930s-1970s (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - About Refregier, circa 1930s-1980s; (15 folders) (Box 21, Folder 15-29)
    - About Refregier, 1970s-1980s; (4 folders) (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - Illustrated by Refregier, circa 1920s-circa 1970s; (6 folders) (Box 22, Folder 5-10)
  - Printed Material, Other Artists/Art-Related, circa 1920s-1980s; 8.2
    - Announcements, Catalogs, Invitations, circa 1930s-1980s; (7 folders) (Box 22, Folder 11-17)
    - General Art-Related, circa 1920s-1970s; (7 folders) (Box 22, Folder 18-24)
    - General Art-Related, 1920s-1970s; (15 folders) (Box 23, Folder 1-15)
    - Literature, circa 1920s-1970s; (5 folders) (Box 23, Folder 16-20)
    - Music and Theater, circa 1920s (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Music and Theater, 1930s-1980s; (6 folders) (Box 24, Folder 1-6)
  - Printed Material, Other Subjects, circa 1920s-1980s; 8.3
    - Magazines, 1940s-1980s; (11 folders) (Box 24, Folder 7-17)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1920s-1960s; (8 folders) (Box 24, Folder 18-25)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-1980s; (2 folders) (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
    - Political, circa 1918-1950s; (19 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 25, Folder 3-21)
    - Political, 1950s-1960s; (21 folders) (Box 26, Folder 1-21)
    - Political, 1960s-1970s; (12 folders) (Box 27, Folder 1-12)
    - Travel, circa 1920s-1970s; (5 folders) (Box 27, Folder 13-17)
    - Travel, Nazi-Era German Travel Brochures, 1930s (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - World Council of Peace, 1950s-1970s; (12 folders) (Box 28, Folder 1-12)
    - Oversized, Political, circa 1918-1950s; (Oversized material from Box 25) (Box 36)
- Scrapbooks, 1930s-1960s; Series 9; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 28, 37
  Scrapbooks are generally in fragmented condition and contain a mixture of photographs, sketches, notes and fragments of writings, and printed material.
  Scrapbook 1 contains clippings, announcements and catalogs; Scrapbook 2 includes photos of Lila Refregier and the Refregier children, agricultural work, and unidentified people, probably including Philip Evergood; Scrapbook 3 contains a mixture of photos and sketches with notes, and draft fragments of essays; Scrapbook 4 contains primarily photos of Guatemala; Scrapbook 5 includs greeting cards with original artwork in addition to several sketches by Refregier; Scrapbook 6 includes printed material related to Refregier's visits to the Soviet Union; Scrapbook 7 relates to a University of Kentucky mural and includes photos of Refregier at work in addition to some FAP photographic division photos; Scrapbooks 8 and 9 contain photos of murals and installations and original artwork; and scrapbook 10 contains news clippings.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1930s; (Oversized material housed in Box 37) (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook 2, circa 1940s; (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 14-15)
  - Scrapbook 3, circa 1950; (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 16-17)
  - Scrapbook 4, circa 1950s; (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 18-19)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1961-1962 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook 6, Loose Printed Material, circa 1960s; (Oversized material housed in Box 37) (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Scrapbook 7 Fragments, circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Scrapbook 8, Fragments, 1930s; (Oversized material housed in Box 37) (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Scrapbook 9, Fragments, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; (Oversized material housed in Box 37) (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Scrapbook 10, Fragments, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; (Oversized material housed in Box 37) (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Oversized, Scrapbook 1, 1930s; (Oversized material from Box 28) (Box 37)
  - Oversized, Scrapbook 6, Loose Printed Material, circa 1960s; (Oversized material from Box 28) (Box 37)
  - Oversized, Scrapbook 8, Fragments, 1930s; (Oversized material from Box 28) (Box 37)
  - Oversized, Scrapbook 9, Fragments, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; (Oversized material from Box 28) (Box 37)
  - Oversized, Scrapbook 10, Fragments, circa 1930s-circa 1950s; (Oversized material from Box 28) (Box 37)
- Artwork, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; Series 10; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 28-30, 36, OVs 40, 41, RDs 42-44
  Artwork by Refregier in the form of loose sketches, primarily in pencil, and 21 sketchbooks, constitutes the bulk of this series. Sketches and cartoons document the development of many of Refregier's mural and tapestry designs. Many of the sketchbooks also contain journal entries and notes. Also found here are prints and reproductions of Refregier's "Peace card" block engravings for every year from 1950-1973, with the exception of 1970.
  Material related to Natural Figure Drawing includes photos and sketches by Refregier and others used in the book and 2 marked up copies of the book. A folder of sketches and text regarding publications for labor organizations, includes two issues of Labor Defender from 1933 and 1934.
  Artwork by others contains artwork by Refregier's children and other unidentified children, and one folder of artwork by others including 7 copies of a woodblock print by Manuel Q. Hernandez, and a pencil sketch and woodblock print by unidentified artists.
  - Artwork by Refregier (Box 28)
    - Loose Sketches, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (2 folders; oversized material housed in OV 40) (Box 28, Folder 26-27)
    - Loose Sketches, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (7 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36 and OV 40) (Box 29, Folder 1-7)
    - Loose Sketches, including Cafe Society Uptown, 1940s; (Oversized material housed in OV 40) (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Loose Sketches, Inc. Colliers, circa 1940s; (Oversized material housed in OV 40) (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Loose Sketches, including Gay Blades Ice Skating Rink, circa 1930s-circa 1940s; (Oversized material housed in OV 40) (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Loose Sketches, including Sarasota, FL, circa 1944; (Oversized material housed in OV 40) (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Loose Sketches, including S. S. Lurline, 1940s; (Oversized material housed in OV 40) (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Loose Sketches, Various, Unidentified, circa 1940s; (Oversized material housed in OV 41, RD 42, RD 43, RD 44) (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Natural Figure Drawing, circa 1940s; (5 folders; oversized material housed in Box 36) (Box 29, Folder 14-18)
    - Peace Cards, 1950s-1970s; (5 folders) (Box 29, Folder 19-23)
    - Sketchbooks, circa 1940s-circa 1960s; (5 folders) (Box 29, Folder 24-28)
    - Sketchbooks, Europe, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Sketchbooks, Mexico, 1963, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Sketchbooks, Mexico, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Sketchbook, Miami, FL, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Sketches and Text Re. Publications for Labor Organizations, 1930s (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Sketches for "Art for Children,", circa 1950s; (includes photos) (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Sketches for Insect Research Center, New York University, circa 1968 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sketches for Urapan Society, circa 1970s (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Artwork by Others (Box 30)
    - By Children, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 7-8)
    - By Others, circa 1950s-circa 1970s (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, Natural Figure Drawing, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box 36)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (Oversized material from Box 28) (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, including Cafe Society Uptown, 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, Inc. Colliers, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, including Gay Blades Ice Skating Rink, circa 1930s-circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, including Sarasota, FL, circa 1944; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, including S. S. Lurline, 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, Various Unidentified, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box OV 41)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, Various Unidentified, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box RD 42)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, Various Unidentified, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box RD 43)
    - Oversized, Loose Sketches, Various Unidentified, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 29) (Box RD 44)
- Photographs, circa 1900-1980s; Series 11; 4.5 Linear feet Boxes 31-35, 39
  Photographs include photographs of Refregier with family, friends and colleagues; Refregier in his studio, including photos of models used for mural painting and for his 1948 book Natural Figure Drawing; Refregier at events such as exhibition openings and parties; and Refregier on trips to the Soviet Union, Mexico and other locations. Also found here are photos of Refregier's artwork and exhibition installations.
  Family photographs include some presumed to picture Refregier's family taken around circa 1900, possibly including the sculptor Vasilief with whom Refregier apprenticed in Paris. Reference to a first wife of Refregier is also inscribed on the verso of one of the photographs.
  Photographs of Refregier at work in the studio and with models, include FAP Photographic Division photos and photos of many models from that period including those used for Refregier's New York World's Fair mural. Some sketches can also be found here.
  Friends and colleagues pictured include Julio de Diego, Marion Greenwood, Rockwell Kent, Pablo O'Higgins and David Siqueiros. There is also a 1936 photo of Margaret Bourke-White, Stuart Davis, Doris Lee, Paul Manship and Lewis Mumford and a group of snapshots from a visit to see Rockwell and Sally Kent at Asgard Farm.
  Photos of events and parties include a dismantled scrapbook and photos from an exhibition opening in 1945 and press photos by Albert A. Freeman, picturing Refregier with Howard Fast, Norman Bel Geddes, Marion Greenwood, John Kingsbury, Yasuo Kuniyoshi and Harry Stockwell. Other events include an exhibiton of Refregier's work in Moscow at the Pushkin Museum of Art.
  Travel photographs of Mexico include a series of photographs and part of a dismantled scrapbook showing Refregier and others at work on the tapestry process.
  The series also contains slide transparencies, primarily of artwork by Refregier and travel to the Soviet Union, circa 1959 and 1960s.
  Of additional note are photographs by others including a photograph by Eliot Elisofon, 2 photographs by Eugene Morley and 4 photographs by Max Yavno, including one of Refregier at work.
  - Refregier, Family and Friends (Box 31)
    - Refregier (Alone), circa 1920s-1979; (Oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Family, circa 1930s-circa 1980s; (7 folders; oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 31, Folder 2-8)
    - Family and Friends/Colleagues, circa 1900-1970s; (5 folders; oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 31, Folder 9-13)
    - Rockwell Kent and Asgard Farm, circa 1960s-circa 1970s (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Album/Scrapbook, circa 1940s; (3 folders) (Box 31, Folder 15-17)
  - Studio and Models (Box 31)
    - Studio and Models, circa 1930s-1970s; (10 folders; oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 31, Folder 18-27)
    - Syracuse University Mural, circa 1962 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Studio and Working with Students, circa 1970s (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Events and Parties (Box 31)
    - Events and Parties, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (4 folders; oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 31, Folder 30-33)
    - Scrapbook-United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, CA, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Paul Robeson and Eleanor Roosevelt at the Wiltwyck School for Boys, circa 1950s (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Bowery Savings Bank Reception, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Exhibition in German Democratic Republic, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - Travel (Box 31)
    - Chile, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - Europe, circa 1950s (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - Mexico, circa 1960s-circa 1970s; (7 folders) (Box 31, Folder 40-46)
    - Soviet Union, 1959-cira 1970s; (7 folders) (Box 32, Folder 1-7)
    - Soviet Union, Samarkand, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - United States, Grand Coulee Dam, circa 1971 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - United States and Unidentified, circa 1930s-circa 1960s; (3 folders) (Box 32, Folder 10-12)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (5 folders) (Box 32, Folder 13-17)
  - Photos of Artwork (Box 32)
    - Exhibitions/Installations, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (3 folders; oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 32, Folder 18-20)
    - Refregier Restaurant Installations by Lionel Freedman, circa 1940s; (Oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Artwork by Refregier, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (13 folders; oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 32, Folder 22-34)
    - Artwork by Refregier, circa 1937; (2 folders) (Box 32, Folder 35-36)
    - Photos of Artwork by Others, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (2 folders) (Box 32, Folder 37-38)
  - Photographs by Others (Box 32)
    - by Eliot Elisofon and Eugene Morley, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; (Oversized material housed in Box 39) (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - by Max Yavno, circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - Snapshots, Artwork, People and Travel, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (5 folders) (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
  - Slide Transparencies, Artwork, People and Travel, circa 1950s-circa 1970s; (1 shoebox) (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Negatives, Artwork, People and Travel, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (13 folders) (Box 35, Folder 1-13)
  - Oversized, Refregier, Family and Friends (Box 39)
    - Oversized, Refregier (Alone), circa 1920s-1979; (Oversized material from Box 31) (Box 39)
    - Oversized, Family, circa 1930s-circa 1980s; (Oversized material from Box 31) (Box 39)
    - Oversized, Family and Friends/Colleagues, circa 1900-1970s; (Oversized material from Box 31) (Box 39)
  - Oversized, Studio and Models, circa 1930s-1970s; (Oversized material from Box 31) (Box 39)
  - Oversized, Events and Parties, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (Oversized material from Box 31) (Box 39)
  - Oversized, Photos of Artwork (Box 39)
    - Oversized, Exhibitions/Installations, circa 1940s-circa 1970s; (3 folders; oversized material from Box 32) (Box 39)
    - Oversized, Refregier Restaurant Installations by Lionel Freedman, circa 1940s; (Oversized material from Box 32) (Box 39)
    - Oversized, Artwork by Refregier, circa 1930s-circa 1970s; (13 folders; oversized material from Box 32) (Box 39)
  - Oversized, Photographs by Others (Box 39)
    - Oversized, by Eliot Elisofon and Eugene Morley, circa 1940s-circa 1950s; (Oversized material from box 32) (Box 39)